手动存档=Manual saving
在游戏中，提供手动存档的功能。\n可以调整存档数量、排序顺序、关闭自动存档等。\nF5手动存档，F8手动读档。\n按键设置请在启用Mod后，进入游戏设置中进行设置。=Provides an in-game function of manually saving.\nYou can adjust the number of saves, sort order, turn off auto-save, etc.\nPress F5 to manually save, F8 to manually load.\nFor key settings, please enter the game settings after enabling the mod.
【！】手动存档=Manual saving!
适配2022.12.9月更新，开启后，将会切换为备用的存档函数，因官方日志里提到了手动存档有概率坏档，因此开启此选项视为接受了坏档的风险。=Adapted to the 2022.12.9 update, after it is enabled, it will switch to the backup archive function, because the official log mentioned that manual archives may have a bad file, so turning on this option is regarded as accepting the risk of bad files.
存档按时间逆序排序=Saves are sorted\nby time
自动存档间隔=Autosave interval
设置自动存档的间隔时间，默认为1则是每个月自动存档一次=Set the interval time for autosave, the default is autosave every 1 month
存档数量=Number of saves
设置存档数量=Set the amount of saves
启用自动存档=Auto-save
关闭后，游戏将不会再自动存档！警告：关闭此项后，请注意及时备份自己的存档！=If turned off, the game will not automatically save anymore!\nWarning: After turning this setting off, please don't forget to save often!
存档逆序排序=Reverse order
开启后，最后保存的存档将显示在最上方=When turned on, the latest save will be displayed at the top.
启用存档数量修改=Save count
开启后，可以修改存档数量。若安装了其他存档修改插件，建议关闭该选项=After enabling, you can modify the number of saves.\nIf you install other save mods, it is recommended to turn this setting off.
保存游戏=Manual save
快速读取=Quick load
快速读档=Quick load
快速存档=Quick save
~更多信息 v1.8~=~ More information v1.8 ~
全部详细人物浮窗=Detailed character\ntooltips
将全部的原版人物浮窗替换为详细文字形式=Replace all the original character tooltips with detailed text tooltips.
人物浮窗显示可请教技能=Show learnable\nskills
在详细人物浮窗中显示可请教的技艺=Show skills that can be consulted in the detailed character tooltip
显示施展时间=Show Cast Time
显示可施展功法的基本施展时间（施展速度为100%时的施展时间）=Show base cast time of skills (As if your Cast Speed is 100%)
功法正逆练=Skill effects
显示功法的正逆练效果=Show Orthodox and Heterodox skill effects on martial arts
书籍正逆练=Book skill effects
显示书籍所载功法的正逆练效果=Show Orthodox and Heterodox skill effects on manuals.
打点显示=Show read chapters
显示催破功法的打点分布=Show which chapters of a manual you've read, and which you haven't.
显示书籍五行属性=Book elements
显示功法书对应功法的五行属性=Show martial art's element on manuals.
按alt显示地块浮窗=Land info display
开启地块浮窗时生效，开启后需同时按住alt显示地块浮窗=Effective when the Tile tooltip setting is on. \nAfter it's on, you need to hold ALT at the same time to show the Land floating window
地块浮窗=Tile tooltip
注意：如果选择按住alt显示，那么需要按住alt再移动鼠标到新的地块来显示浮窗=Note: If you choose to Hold ALT to display, then you need to hold ALT and then move the mouse to the new tile for the tooltip to be shown.
从官方mod拿来的功能，额外增加了资源显示=The function brought from the official mod, with additional resource display
浮窗显示坐标和人物ID=NPC's XYZ and ID
村民人物浮窗=Villagers info
为居民信息块（工作派遣等）增加鼠标浮窗（头像边上的空白处）=Add mouse floating window (blank space by the avatar) for villager information blocks (job dispatch, etc.)
人物浮窗显示真名=NPC real name
从官方mod拿来的功能，在人物浮窗中显示法号对应的真实姓名=A function brought from the official mod to show the real name corresponding to the ID in the character floating window
学习进度=Study progress
开启正逆练显示时生效，显示功法、功法书籍的读书、修炼进度，目前显示位置不太好，不喜欢可以关闭=Effective when skill effects setting is turned on. Show the reading and cultivation progress of martial arts and manuals. \nThis display isn't very good, you can turn it off if you don’t like it.
对话人物浮窗=Tooltips\nin dialogue
为事件界面（人物对话互动等）的左右两个人物增加鼠标浮窗=Add an ability to see tooltips of the characters you're interacting with by hovering your mouse over them
显示不传之秘=Hidden arts
显示门派武学列表中的不传之秘=Show sect's hidden martial arts.
左侧人物浮窗=Character\ntooltips
为地图左侧人物列表增加鼠标浮窗=Add mouse floating window to the list of characters on the left side of the screen
地块浮窗显示人物列表=Tile tooltip\nshows NPCs
地块浮窗高亮较多资源=Highlight res
在地块浮窗中将100以上的资源以不同颜色显示=In the Land floating window, when there are more than 100 resources it will be displayed in different color
显示人物特性=Show NPC traits
在详细文字式左侧人物浮窗中显示人物特性=Show NPC traits if you have Character tooltips or Villager tooltips set to Detailed
居民人物浮窗=Villager\ntooltips
居住、扩建等界面已安排的人物上=Tooltips of the villagers on the Dormitory, Upgrade, and other menus.
显示人物持有物品数=NPC's\nItems
在详细人物浮窗中显示人物持有的此数量的最高品级物品，为0则不显示=If your "Character tooltips" set to "Detailed", show this amount of highest-grade items the character holds in the tooltip. Put to 0 to turn off.
显示人物擅长功法数=NPC's\nSkills
在详细人物浮窗中显示人物会的此数量的最高品级功法，为0则不显示=If your "Character tooltips" set to "Detailed", show this amount of highest-grade skills the character knows in the tooltip. Put to 0 to turn off.
突出正逆练区别=Ortho/Hetero\nDifference
标红正练特效与逆练特效之间的区别=<color\=#FF0000>(Doesn't work with the English translation mod. Please put it to "Disabled")</color>\nShows the difference between Orthodox and Heterodox skill effects.
始终关闭=Disabled
按住alt键时开启=Hold ALT to display
始终开启=Always on
关闭=Turn off
原版=Original
详细文字=Detailed
不显示=Don't show
按住alt显示=Hold ALT to display
始终显示（原版）=Always display (original)
显示可见特性=Show visible traits
显示全部特性=Show all traits
称号=Title
性别=Gender
魅力=Charm
心情=Mood
立场=Standpoint
好感=REL
从属=From
身份=Identity
名誉=Fame
轮回=Incarnation
sr:"^<color\=#BDBDBDFF>     如果正练：(.*)$"=<color\=#BDBDBDFF>     Orthodox：$1 
sr:"^<color\=#BDBDBDFF>     如果逆练：(.*)$"=<color\=#BDBDBDFF>     Heterodox：$1 
sr:"^     当前：(.*)$"=     Cur.：$1 
太吾优化=Taiwu Optimization
立即显示=Display immediately
1.25x（推荐）=1.25X (Recommended)
1.5x（推荐）=1.5X (Recommended)
2x（推荐）=2x (Recommended)
立绘延迟加载=Delay art loading
使立绘加载变为延迟加载，缓解加载大量立绘时的卡顿现象。=Make art loading delayed to ease the lag when loading a large number of art.
滚动列表优化=Scroll list fix
为滚动列表添加缓存功能，避免大量重复刷新导致游戏卡顿。=Add cache function for scrolling list to avoid a lot of repeated refreshes that cause game lag.
立绘加载淡入时间=Art loading time
<color\=#FF0000>[需开启立绘延迟加载]</color>在立绘加载后，淡入显示的时间。对立绘淡入感觉不适可以设置为[立即显示]=<color\=#FF0000>[Requires "Delay art loading" to be turned on]</color> The time to fade into the display after the artwork is loaded. \nIf you feel uncomfortable with the fade-in, you can set it to [Display immediately].
在立绘加载后，淡入显示的时间。对立绘淡入感觉不适可以设置为[立即显示]=The time to fade into the display after the artwork is loaded. \nIf you feel uncomfortable with the fade-in, you can set it to [Display immediately].
奇遇移动优化=Optimize adventure\nmovement
使奇遇移动更加流畅（不用走一下等一下）=Make the adventure movement smoother (don't have to stop for a moment to wait)
奇遇镜头跟随=Adventure camera\nfollows
<color\=#FF0000>[需开启奇遇移动优化]</color>使奇遇移动过程中镜头跟随人物=<color\=#FF0000>[Requires "Optimize adventure movement" to be turned on]</color> Makes the camera follow the character during the adventure movement
奇遇移动倍速=Adventure speed\nmultiplier
奇遇界面的移动速度倍速。=The movement speed of your character in the adventure.
奇遇展开倍速=Adventure unfolding\nmultiplier
奇遇界面的奇遇格子展开速度倍速。=The speed multiplier for adventure tile unfolding.
大地图移动优化=World map\noptimization
优化大地图移动，使移动更加流畅。=Optimize the movement on world map to make it smoother.
大地图线性移动=World map\nmove animation
<color\=#FF0000>[需开启大地图移动优化]</color>使大地图移动变为线性移动动画，在连续移动时更流畅。=<color\=#FF0000>[Requires "World map optimization" to be turned on]</color> Makes the world map movement into a linear animation, which is smoother when moving continuously.
大地图移动倍速=World map\nanimation speed
<color\=#FF0000>[需开启大地图移动优化]</color>大地图的移动速度倍速。=<color\=#FF0000>[Requires "World map optimization" to be turned on]</color> The movement speed on the world map.
过月优化=New month\noptimization
对过月组织成员排序进行优化，加快过月速度。=Optimize the sorting of the organization members on starting new month to speed up new month loading.
关闭过月秘闻=Turn off secrets
关闭过月产生的秘闻，加快过月速度。=Turn off the secret messages to speed up new month loading.
使用淡入对话框=Fade-in dialog
将对话框动画改为淡入=Change the dialog animation to fade in
对话框弹出动画时间=Dialog pop-up
人物对话框的弹出动画时间。=Pop-up animation time of the character's dialog box
快速进入战斗=Fast combat start
使战斗开始提前，不需要再等tips结束。=Make the combat start earlier, no need to wait for TIPS to end.
快速战斗结算=Fast combat end
使战斗结算界面动画速度更快。=Make the combat settlement screen animation faster.
战斗结算倍速=Combat end speed
战斗结算界面的动画倍速。=Animation speed of the combat settlement interface.
基础施展时间=Cast time
技艺换书=Fine arts
门派换书=Martial arts
全门派换书=Whole sect book exchange
在门派势力页面增加门派换书功能，直接和整个门派的所有人换书，可以筛选功法种类，品级和总纲正逆练\n添加了地点限制的设置，可以限制只在门派地格才能换书\n添加换技艺书功能，因为换技艺书有好感度要求，所以不能直接换，找到需要的书再去找持有者换吧=Adds a book exchange function on the sect power page, allowing to directly exchange books with everyone in the entire sect.\nYou can filter the types of exercises, grades and general outlines.\nAdded location restriction settings, you can limit the exchange to the sect tile.\nThe function of changing skill books is added. Because changing skill books requires Favor, you can't change them directly. Find the book you need and go to the holder to exchange it.
地点限制=Location
只有在门派地格才能换书=Can exchange books only on the sect tile
捏人优化框架=Art Enhancement Framework
输出调试日志，方便排错=Output debugging log, convenient for errors
输出调试日志=Logs
一个可以替换捏人素材的框架。允许Mod作者们自制替换Mod包来替换捏人素材。 使用方式请B站搜索 宵夜97 观看视频。=A framework for replacing art materials. \nAllows mod authors to make their own replacement mod packs to replace the art materials.\nFor more information look up 宵夜97's videos on bilibili.
男性五官发型特征美化=Male beautification (facial features, hairstyle)
女性全体型美化（仅发型脸型）=Female beautification (hairstyle, face shape)
女性全体型美化（仅五官特征）=Female beautification (facial features)
胡子消失术&驻颜术=Beard disappearance & Face lift
依赖于宵夜97制作的【捏人优化框架】，只是删除了所有胡子和皱纹的贴图。=Created relying on the [Art Enhancement Framework] by 宵夜97, deletes all textures of facial hair and wrinkles
男性中体型服饰优化=Male medium body clothing beautification
优化男性中体型的服饰，修正了所有服装脖子和头部的衔接（订阅了男性美化的朋友不用担心飞头术了）。细节大改：✳百花三件校服（不再是只是粉绿，细节重绘）✳bug衣（站姿重画）✳引导衣（重画）✳衮龙黄袍（重画）✳璇女低阶校服（重画）✳空桑低阶校服（重画）选色大改：✳纹绣深衣✳峨眉三件校服（不再只是粉色）=Optimized the costumes for men with medium body types, and corrected the connection between the neck and head of all costumes (friends who have subscribed to male beautification don't have to worry about flying heads). \n\nMajor changes in details: \n>Baihua three school uniforms (no longer just pink and green, details repainted) \n>bug clothes (standing posture redraw) \n>Guiding clothes (redraw) \n>Gunlong yellow robe (redraw) \n>Xuannu low High-level school uniforms (repainting) \n>Kongsang low-level school uniforms (repainting) color selection major changes: \n>Embroidered deep clothes \n>Emei three-piece school uniforms (no longer just pink)
一起来健♂身=Let's get fit together!
替换了中小男性的0号服装，虽然扒光了但却正好卡在用不着打码的程度=Replaced the naked body of small and medium size males. Although it was stripped off, it was just stuck at the level where no coding was needed.
小孩儿=Cute children
美化年幼外观，并替换了男孩的各种毛没长齐的发型，让村民从小吃可爱长大（长残）。=Beautifies the appearance of children, and replaces the boy's various hair did not grow hair, so that the villagers grew up from a snack cute (long disability)
正在展开绘卷…=Unfolding the scroll...
基础设置=Settings
进入绘卷=Enter the painting roll
十世绘卷=Ten Scrolls
继续=Play
还原=Load
删除=Delete
每月：=per month:
完整=Full
残缺=Half
亡佚=Lost
△残缺=△Half
输入姓名进行查找…=Enter a name to find...
门派功法=Martial arts
鬼术=Ghost
神力=Divine
0 日=0days
1 日=1day
2 日=2days
3 日=3days
4 日=4days
5 日=5days
6 日=6days
7 日=7days
8 日=8days
9 日=9days
10 日=10days
11 日=11days
12 日=12days
13 日=13days
14 日=14days
15 日=15days
16 日=16days
17 日=17days
18 日=18days
19 日=19days
20 日=20days
21 日=21days
22 日=22days
23 日=23days
24 日=24days
25 日=25days
26 日=26days
27 日=27days
28 日=28days
29 日=29days
30 日=30days
能够使用「出战」指令在短时间内代替主战者进行战斗。=Use 「Swap」 order to swap with your teammate for a short while.
能够使用「催发」指令增加主战者功法的施展进度。=Use 「Haste」 order to speed up the cast time of a skill in use.
能够使用「迅进」指令拉近主战者与敌人之间的距离。=Use 「Push」 order to shorten the distance between you and your enemy.
能够使用「拉回」指令拉开主战者与敌人之间的距离。=Use 「Pull」 order to widen the distance between you and your enemy.
能够使用「攻击」指令攻击敌人。=Use 「Attack」 order to attack the enemy.
能够使用「防御」指令施展护体功法为主战者抵挡敌人的攻击。=Use 「Defend」 order to make your teammate defend you with an Aegis skill.
能够使用「疗伤」指令为主战者疗伤。=Use 「Heal」 order to heal your injuries.
能够使用「驱毒」指令为主战者驱毒。=Use 「Detox」 order to detox.
能够使用「还护」指令为主战者消除破绽。=Use 「Mend」 order to heal your Weak Points.
能够使用「解穴」指令为主战者解开封穴。=Use 「Release」 order to heal your Sealed Acupoints.
能够使用「掠阵」指令在短时间内增加主战者的力道、精妙、迅疾。=Use 「Guide」 order to increase your Might, Finesse, and Swiftness for a short while.
能够使用「警示」指令在短时间内增加主战者的卸力、拆招、闪避。=Use 「Warn」 order to increase your Diversion, Parry, and Evasion for a short while.
能够使用「真气」类指令将自身的真气传输给主战者。=Use 「True Qi」 order to make your teammate transfer some of their True Qi to you.
能够使用「替命」指令为主战者分担外伤或内伤。=Use 「Sacrifice」 order to make your teammate share injuries with you.
可解锁此建筑=Unlockable
自动=Auto
关=OFF
开=ON
小=S
中=M
大=L
【奇遇人物】=【Participants】
<color\=#e5cd5d>金刚</color>生<color\=#acd5ff>玄阴</color>=<color\=#e5cd5d>Metal</color>\ngenerates\n<color\=#acd5ff>Water</color>
<color\=#e5cd5d>金刚</color>克<color\=#c682ff>紫霞</color>=<color\=#e5cd5d>Metal</color>\nrestrains\n<color\=#c682ff>Wood</color>
<color\=#acd5ff>玄阴</color>生<color\=#c682ff>紫霞</color>=<color\=#acd5ff>Water</color>\ngenerates\n<color\=#c682ff>Wood</color>
<color\=#acd5ff>玄阴</color>克<color\=#fc514c>纯阳</color>\n=<color\=#acd5ff>Water</color>\nrestrains\n<color\=#fc514c>Fire</color>
<color\=#c682ff>紫霞</color>生<color\=#fc514c>纯阳</color>=<color\=#c682ff>Wood</color>\ngenerates\n<color\=#fc514c>Fire</color>
<color\=#c682ff>紫霞</color>克<color\=#68eb6b>归元</color>=<color\=#c682ff>Wood</color>\nrestrains\n<color\=#68eb6b>Earth</color>
<color\=#fc514c>纯阳</color>生<color\=#68eb6b>归元</color>=<color\=#fc514c>Fire</color>\ngenerates\n<color\=#68eb6b>Earth</color>
<color\=#fc514c>纯阳</color>克<color\=#e5cd5d>金刚</color>=<color\=#fc514c>Fire</color>\nrestrains\n<color\=#e5cd5d>Metal</color>
<color\=#68eb6b>归元</color>生<color\=#e5cd5d>金刚</color>=<color\=#68eb6b>Earth</color>\ngenerates\n<color\=#e5cd5d>Metal</color>
<color\=#68eb6b>归元</color>克<color\=#acd5ff>玄阴</color>=<color\=#68eb6b>Earth</color>\nrestrains\n<color\=#acd5ff>Water</color>
五行生克\n=Element Chart
运转完毕=Done
当前真气状况=True Qi Status
按住=Hold 
全部=All
重要=Major
次要=Minor
其它\n=Misc
战斗形象=Art
命名=Name
鸡=chicken
清理=Clear
选择铭刻=Select Imprint
封面图片=Cover
详情图片=Pictures
实时修改人物信息（非官方修复版）=Character Modification in Real Time (Unofficial Repair)
姓名或ID=Name/ID
请输人物姓名或ID=Character name...
修改人物信息=Modify Character
改变特性=Traits
修改人物特性=Modify Traits
特性表=Traits Table
人物特性表=Trait Table
查看当前=View Current
请输人物特性的名称=Trait name...
添加特性=Add Trait
移除特性=Remove Trait
改变姓名=Name
修改人物姓名=Modify Name
新的姓=Surname
新的名=Name
（修改姓名后，需要重新打开人物窗口，才会显示新的姓名。）=(After modifying the name, you have to re-open character menu.)
（注意：不可以对固定生成的人物改名！）=(Note: You cannot rename fixed character!)
确定=Agree
改变立场=Standpoint
修改人物立场=Modify Standpoint
选择立场=Standpoint
改变外貌=Appearance
修改人物外貌=Modify Appearance
打开修改面板=Open modification menu
随机天人=Heavenly
调整五官（天人）=Face
导入外貌=Import
导出外貌=Export
资质成长=Growth
修改人物资质成长=Modify Growth
改变武学资质成长=Martial Arts
改变技艺资质成长=Fine Arts
均衡=Balanced
早熟=Early
晚成=Late
改变X取向=Orientation
修改人物X取向=Modify Orientation
选择X取向=Orientation
异性恋=Hetero
同性恋=Homo
改变声誉=Reputation
修改声誉事件=Modify Reputation
增加声誉事件=Add
移除声誉事件=Remove
<就空着>=<Empty>
<color\=#F8E0CAFF>五方神龙</color>=<color\=#F8E0CAFF>Divine Dragons of Five Regions</color>
五方神龙=Divine Dragons of Five Regions
r:"^“春山茂，春景晖，满城春花似雪飞，\n劝君莫逐东流水，且共春风载酒归……”\n\n只听“宛渠之民”口中欢声唱着歌谣，\n摇摇摆摆来到跟前，朝着(.*)抱拳躬身，施礼贺岁，\n随后又从口袋中取出一身衣袍，递到(.*)手中……$"=""Spring mountains lush, spring scenery bright, city blooming with spring flowers like snow in flight,\nI urge you not to chase the flowing eastward stream, but to return home with wine carried by the spring breeze..."\nListening to the "Person from Wanqu" singing joyfully, swaying as they come over, they bow respectfully to $1, offering New Year's greetings. Then, they take out a robe from their pocket and hand it to the $2..."
 （这是何物？）=（What is this?）
r:"^“除岁方过，佳节初至，\n我和伙伴们特意为你裁制了这件新衣，\n望你今后多喜乐，少烦忧，所求皆如愿，所行化坦途！”\n\n“宛渠之民”说罢，抬起双手舞了舞衣袖，\n又欢快地唱起歌来，随后便消失在了(.*)的视野里……$"=""As the old year passes and the festival begins anew,\nMy companions and I have tailored this new garment for you,\nMay you find abundant joy and less worry henceforth,\nMay your desires be fulfilled and your path be smooth!"\n\nAfter speaking, the "Person from Wanqu" raised their hands and waved their sleeves, then sang cheerfully before disappearing from $1's sight."
 （如此便好……）=（That's good...）
文件大小=File Size
发布日期=Released
更新日期=Updated
世界地图=World Map
单次获得遗惠=Per Completion
已完成次数=Completed
- 具体获取条件：=- Condition:
- 世界细节影响：=- Difficulty:
殊=S
普=N
完=Done


